About me

Adviser/Influencer Mindset, with over 10 years of experience in Support Services and IT roles. I have honed advanced critical thinking and problem-solving skills, allowing me for an efficient and seamless adaptation to new environments. My background encompasses Support services, data analysis, Access administration, and Project Management. Currently, I am involved in global support projects related to Celergo Payroll Processing, including Data Integration Services, Process Model, Methodology, SLAs, and RCA analysis. Familiarized with Power BI reporting, Microsoft Project and Monitoring by APM (Dynatrace)...

I am an enthusiast of blockchain, IoT, and Big Data. Captivated by their revolutionary potential to reshape industries and unlock unprecedented possibilities.

Professional Experiences

Senior Global Service Support Representative at ADP

October, 2023 - Present

SME in Celergo payroll processing and support model application, working in collaboration with cross-functional teams, employing an iterative and incremental project management approach for Transitions to Service and Support

Contributing in project management with Stakeholders, especially in the planning, analysis, and execution phases

Involved in data analysis, interpreting data, creating reports, and deriving insights to support decision-making processes

Making part of Hypercare support, Demos and releases calls

Global Service Support Representative at ADP

March, 2021 - September 2023

Participating in CS teams projects: Service Catalog/Scope, Transition to Service, Service Readiness, monitoring. And sharing knowledge management with internal teams by sharing communications, training and Documentation related to Process Model, new enhancements and releases..

Managing internal team queues and ensuring adherence to SLA timelines and priorities, particularly in escalations

Collaborating actively in data integration projects, Monitoring Live Client data integration errors, reporting technical failures, SORs configuration/update, Escalating Implementation issues and documenting RCAs

Performing data analysis and modeling, extracting insights and generating reports for team performance and SRs internal stats Communicating findings, publishing documentation, and providing recommendations to stakeholders

Abdelfettah Chafii Echouhani

Senior Global Service Support Representative

https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdelchafii/

abdel.chafii@outlook.com

Barcelona (08014) Spain (+34) 662118064

Skills & Knowledge

ADP HR systems

Project Management

Integration Support: WFN, Oracle, Workday, Lifion, Successfactors..

Microsoft Dynamics CRM

Power BI

Microsoft Project

Dynatrace

Ticketing Systems: Jira Service Management, Siebel, Remedy

Packet Tracer

Data Integration

Sharepoint & Confluence

Basic SAP skills

Microsoft Office - Excel

HTML & CSS

Technical & Functional skills

Collaborating with the Products team. Providing system support and configuration training. Additionally, assisting in knowledge transfer, new releases and service transition sessions

More projects: Access Request escalations, GDPR Data Purge, Payroll Integration configuration.

IT Support Analyst - T2 at Computacenter (Airbus)

July, 2014 - July, 2020

Focused on Providing Support to L1 Analysts, covering Escalations and High priority SRs for Airbus Account Admin users/Privileged contacts

IT Support Analyst at Computacenter (Air Liquide)

April 2013 - July 2014

Multilingual IT Support for EN, SP, and FR speakers

Booking/Support Team Agent at Avis Budget Group

March, 2021 - Present

Booking & Service Desk Support tasks

Education

Human Sciences Hassan II University - Casablanca 1998 - 2000 Law - Master Not completed

ISTA - OFPPT 2000 - 2002 Technicien Spécialisé en Restauration

Languages

English, French, Spanish, Catalan and Arabic

Courses & Certifications

ADP - Celergo Learning Path

ADP - Project Management course

Agile Scrum Master Certification Training

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure
- Certified Foundations
Associate - Udemy

Data Integration Fundamentals - Udemy

Oracle Data Integrator (ODI) 12c Developer Course

AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials

Cybersecurity Essentials - Cisco Academy

Introduction to Packet Tracer - Cisco Academy

Cloud Computing - Google

Chat GPT courses - Udemy

NDG Linux Essentials - Cisco Academy